Women's movement collection (Candace Parker collector)
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Women's movement collection (Candace Parker collector)
1969 - 1976
F-165
Q106660546
13 cm of textual records 21 newspapers
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Parker, Candace
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the contents of the collection.
In 1970 Candace Parker was a member of the Vancouver Women's Caucus and a graduate student at the University of British Columbia. For a sociology class, Parker and Sibylle Klein wrote an essay, "Developing An Ideology: the Feminist Movement in North America," which drew upon Parker's experiences in Women's Caucus. Candace Parker was also interviewed by Frances Wasserlein and the transcript of that interview is contained in the Frances Wasserlein fonds, F-162.
The collection consists of research material collected by Candace Parker in the course of preparing her essay plus some additional feminist literature acquired afterwards. Includes notes and drafts, news clippings, reprints, broadsheets, position papers, briefs, newsletters, and newspapers.
The materials were arranged by the archivist. The original arrangement (2001) had no series; files were arranged alphabetically, items (newspapers) chronologically. In 2012, the archivist created separate series for the subject files (retained in alphabetical order) and for the newspapers, with a file created for each newspaper title.
Parker, Candace; Wasserlein, Frances; Women
Acquired from Frances Wasserlein. Donated to the SFU Archives by Candace Parker in 2001.
All accessions have been processed as of March 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Candace Parker originally gave the material to Frances Wasserlein to use for her thesis with the understanding that the material would eventually be donated to an archives.
Also see the inventories for the Frances Wasserlein fonds, F-162; Andrea Lebowitz's women's movement collection, F-164; and Anne Roberts' women's movement collection, F-166.
The files are open with no restrictions.
Biographical information on Candace Parker is available in the appendices to the hardcopy finding aid available in the Archives reading room.
- Subject files, 1969 - 1976; F-165-1; 12 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of Parker's subject and research files; includes a copy of her paper co-authored with Sibylle Klein, "Developing An Ideology: the Feminist Movement in North America." Record types include notes and drafts, news clippings, reprints, broadsheets, position papers, briefs, and newsletters.
  Arrangement was supplied by the archivist. File 1 represents Parker's essay; the remaining files are arranged alphabetically.
  Textual records
  All files are open with no access restrictions.
  - Developing An Ideology: The Feminist Movement in North America, Klein / Parker, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Sibylle Klein; Textual records
    Open
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-1.
  - Abortion / Birth Control, 1969 - 1970; F-165-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-2.
  - Anthropology / Sociology, 1969 - 1970; F-165-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-3.
  - Beauty Pageants, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-4.
  - Childcare, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-5.
  - National Organization for Women (N.O.W.), 1970; F-165-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    National Organization for Women; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-6.
  - Notes and drafts 1/2, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-7.
  - Notes and drafts 2/2, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-8.
  - Sexuality, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-9.
  - Vancouver Women's Caucus, 1969 - 1970; F-165-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Vancouver Women's Caucus; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-10.
  - Western Canadian Women's News Service, 1976; F-165-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Western Canadian Women's News Service; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-11.
  - Women's Liberation - Berkeley, Bay Area (California), 1969 - 1970; F-165-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-12.
  - Women's Liberation - Canada, [197-?]; F-165-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-13.
  - Women's Liberation - general, 1969 - 1970; F-165-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-14.
  - Women's Liberation - Vancouver / Victoria, 1969 - 1975; F-165-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-15.
  - Work, 1969 - 1973; F-165-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-16.
  - Work - housework, 1970; F-165-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 165-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-0-17.
- Newspapers, 1969 - 1972; F-165-2; 21 newspapers
  Series consists of copies of published newspapers collected by Parker in the course of her research. Titles include the Students for a Democratic Society New Left Note, The Daily Gater, The Ubyssey (UBC), The Pedestal, It Aint Me Babe, People's World, Right On!, Young Socialist Forum, Women's Liberation (Reed College), New Leaf, the Women's Liberated Georgia Straight, and Off Our Backs.
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  - SDS New Left Note, [ca 1969]; F-165-2-0-0-1 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Students for a Democratic Society; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-18.18, F-165-item1.
  - The Daily Gater, 1969; F-165-2-0-0-2 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-18.1, F-165-item4.
  - The Ubyssey, 1969 - 1971; F-165-2-0-0-3 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    University of British Columbia (UBC); Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-18.19, F-165-0-0-18.21, F-165-item3, F-165-item14.
  - The Pedestal, 1969 - 1972; F-165-2-0-0-4 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-0-0-18.8, F-165-0-0-18.9, F-165-0-0-18.10, F-165-0-0-18.11, F-165-0-0-18.12, F-165-0-0-18.13, F-165-0-0-18.14, F-165-item2, F-165-item13, F-165-item16, F-165-item17, F-165-item18, F-165-item19, F-165-item20.
  - It Aint Me Babe, 1970; F-165-2-0-0-5 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item5, F-165-item10, F-165-item11, F-165-0-0-18.3, F-165-0-0-18.4, F-165-0-0-18.5.
  - People's World, 1970; F-165-2-0-0-6 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item6, F-165-0-0-18.15.
  - Right On!, 1970; F-165-2-0-0-7 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item7, F-165-0-0-18.17.
  - Young Socialist Forum, 1970; F-165-2-0-0-8 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item8, F-165-0-0-18.20.
  - Women's Liberation - Reed College, 1970; F-165-2-0-0-9 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Reed College; Textual records
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item9, F-165-0-0-18.16.
  - New Leaf, 1971; F-165-2-0-0-10 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item12, F-165-0-0-18.6.
  - Women's Liberated Georgia Straight, 1971; F-165-2-0-0-11 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item15, F-165-0-0-18.2.
  - Off Our Backs, 1972; F-165-2-0-0-12 (Newspaper box 165-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-165-item21.